<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Esteban Moro</title>
    <link>/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Esteban Moro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Important relationships are not bursty</title>
      <link>/2018/11/important-relationships-are-not-bursty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/important-relationships-are-not-bursty/</guid>
      <description>What are the properties of a long-lasting relationship? This important question as intrigued the social scientists during the last decades and has triggered numerous publications, surveys and experiments to detect what patterns are behind social relationships that persist. Probably the most famous finding is that of Granovetter who proposed that strong relationships are the ones more likely to persist in the future. And what is a strong relationship? According to Granovetter, a strong relationship is that with high intensity (a lot of interactions), intimacy (mutual confiding) and large structural redundancy (lots of common friends).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Science for kids!</title>
      <link>/2018/11/network-science-for-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/network-science-for-kids/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite activities is to teach my field or research network science to high-schoolers. We (together with my colleague Cristina Brändle) have been doing that from our university to the local high schools in Madrid. Since they know concepts like equations, probability or geometry, it is somehow easy to show them concepts like what is a network, small world, friendship paradox or centrality. We usually have transparencies and allow them to work on Excel to perform some calculations which works well to understand the basic concepts of networks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>